rba.gov.au 2014-02-16

# RBA: Privacy Policy

The Reserve Bank of Australia respects the privacy of visitors to its website. This page sets out the Reserve Bank's current practices concerning information collection and dissemination through this website. It also tells you about access to and updating of personal information, and enquiries and complaints about the Bank's use of personal information. These sections cover all personal information the Bank holds. 

##### Go To

  * Collection of Information 
  * Security of Information 
  * Identification 
  * Use and Disclosure of Information 
  * Access to or amendment of Personal Information 
  * Enquiries and Complaints 

### Collection of Information

#### Logged Information

When you connect to our website, our Internet service provider (ISP) logs the following information, provided by your browser, for statistical purposes: 

  * the type of browser and operating system you are using; 
  * your top level domain name (for example .com, .gov, .au, .uk, etc.); 
  * the address of the referring website (i.e. the website that directed you to our website); and 
  * your server's IP address (a number which is unique to the machine through which you are connected to the Internet: usually one of your service provider's machines). 

In addition, our server logs the following information: 

  * the date and time of your visit; and 
  * the address of the pages accessed and the documents downloaded. 

Information from ISP logs will only be disclosed if the Reserve Bank is required by law to do so. 

#### E-mail Addresses

We will record your e-mail address if you: 

  * send us an e-mail message; 
  * purchase a publication via our online Publication Form; 
  * apply for a job; or
  * register for our e-mail notification service. 

Your e-mail address will only be used for the purpose for which you provide it, and will not be added to a mailing list or provided to a third party unless you request that this be done. We will not disclose your e-mail address or personal information without your consent. 

#### E-mail Service (Subscriptions)

Some pages of this website provide the facility for visitors to join our free e-mail notification service. To join, visitors must provide a valid e-mail address. 

Personal details provided for the purpose of our e-mail service are stored on a separate server owned and managed by our e-mail list management service provider L-Soft international, Inc. Your e-mail details can only be accessed by authorised L-Soft and authorised Reserve Bank staff. 

#### Job Applications

Please do not submit your personal information if you do not want your information to be dealt with in the ways described in this policy. 

By submitting an application or registering interest in employment with the Reserve Bank of Australia, you will supply us with personal information, including application data and contact details (‘your information’). 

Once submitted, your personal information will be stored on a separate server owned and managed by our recruitment application service provider PageUp People. Your personal information can only be accessed by authorised staff at PageUp People and Reserve Bank of Australia. 

Once submitted, Reserve Bank of Australia staff will use the information you have provided to: 

  * assess and administer your application for employment; 
  * communicate with you in relation to your application; 
  * comply with any legal or regulatory obligations; and 
  * monitor and review our recruitment practices. 

If your application is unsuccessful, the Reserve Bank of Australia may retain your information on file and may contact you if a suitable employment opportunity arises. Please contact us if you do not wish the Reserve Bank of Australia to retain your information on file. If your application is successful, the Reserve Bank of Australia will retain your information as part of your employment records. 

You may request access to your information (and for amendments to be made to your information) at any time by contacting us at [careers@rba.gov.au](mailto:careers@rba.gov.au)  

#### Search terms and phrases

Search terms and phrases that you use to reach our website, including those used via the Reserve Bank website search facility, are collected, but are not associated with any other information that we collect. We use these search terms to find out what visitors look for on our website, and to improve our services. 

#### Cookies

The Reserve Bank does not use ‘cookies’ to get information about you or your use of our website. A ‘cookie’ is a file that could be placed on your hard drive by a website without your knowledge to allow it to monitor how the site is used. 

Any changes to our ‘cookies’ policy will be notified on this page. 

#### Links to other sites

Links to other websites are provided to help us meet your needs but the Reserve Bank is not responsible for the content or privacy policies of those sites. Our Disclaimer provides further information. 

### Security of Information

If you provide the Reserve Bank with personal information via e-mail or any other means, your information may become part of the records of the Reserve Bank. The Reserve Bank takes all reasonable care to secure personal information and protect it against unauthorised access and misuse. If you are submitting personal or other information over the Internet please note that, while all attempts are made to ensure security of information transmitted to this site, there is a possibility that information you send could be seen by a third party while it is in transit. 

Information from our ISP logs will only be disclosed if the Reserve Bank is required by law to do so. 

When required by law, e.g. search warrant or subpoena, information requested (including an inspection of our ISP logs) will be provided to law enforcement agencies, courts or regulatory bodies. 

### Identification

No attempt will be made by the Reserve Bank to identify visitors or their browsing activities except where required by law or when authorised by Reserve Bank management in connection with investigations into possible breaches of the law. 

### Use and Disclosure of Information

Your personal information submitted via the website will only be used for the purpose for which you provide it, and will not be added to a mailing list or provided to a third party unless you request that this be done. We will not disclose your personal information submitted via the website without your consent except where required or authorised by law or when authorised by Reserve Bank management in connection with investigations into possible breaches of the law. 

As part of the Reserve Bank's commitment to meeting the needs of the public for information about its policies and operations, the Reserve Bank may occasionally conduct non-compulsory surveys of users of Reserve Bank information. Prior to collecting survey results, the Reserve Bank will: 

  * advise survey recipients of the purpose of the survey; and 
  * offer recipients a facility to exit the survey at any time. 

### Access to or amendment of Personal Information

If you wish to access any personal information the Reserve Bank holds about you, or amend or correct personal information that you have submitted via the Reserve Bank website or which the Reserve Bank has collected from any other source, you can forward your request to: 

For access to or amendments to job applications: **E-mail** |  [careers@rba.gov.au](mailto:careers@rba.gov.au)  
---|---  
**Phone** | +61 2 9551 9649  
**Fax** | +61 2 9551 8060  
**Post** |  The Manager  
Recruitment and Workforce Planning  
Human Resources  
Reserve Bank of Australia  
GPO Box 3947  
SYDNEY NSW 2001  
AUSTRALIA   
For access to or amendment of any other information:  **E-mail** |  [rbainfo@rba.gov.au](mailto:rbainfo@rba.gov.au)  
---|---  
**Feedback form** |   www.rba.gov.au/forms/feedback-form/   
**Phone** | +61 2 9551 9720  
**Fax** | +61 2 9551 8033  
**Post** |  Head of Information Department  
Reserve Bank of Australia  
GPO Box 3947  
SYDNEY NSW 2001  
AUSTRALIA   
  
In some situations permitted by law the Reserve Bank may deny your request for access or correction. If we do this we will tell you why. 

### Enquiries and Complaints

If you would like more information about the Reserve Bank's approach to privacy, or you have any concern about the way the Reserve Bank has handled your personal information, please contact our Privacy Officer by: 

**E-mail** |  [privacy@rba.gov.au](mailto:privacy@rba.gov.au)  
---|---  
**Phone** | +61 2 9551 9610  
**Fax** | +61 2 9551 8035  
**Post** |  The Privacy Officer  
Reserve Bank of Australia  
GPO Box 3947  
SYDNEY NSW 2001  
AUSTRALIA   
  
If you have concerns about the Reserve Bank's handling of any personal information we may ask you to put them in writing so that we can fully understand and investigate the issues you have raised.
